## Xiaotian Han

E-mail: han@tamu.edu

Homepage: ahxt.github.io

Ph.D. Student Department of Computer Science & Engineering Texas A&M University

## Research Interests

I am currently a 4th-year Ph.D. student in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at Texas A&M University. I am working at the DATA Lab under the supervision of Prof. Xia (Ben) Hu. My research focuses on graph learning, fairness in machine learning and automated machine learning. Specifically, my research lies in the following topics:

- **Graph Learning**: large-scale graph neural networks, graph augmentation
- Fairness: egocentric fairness and structure fairness in graph neural network
- AutoML: automated recommendation, automated information extraction

### **Education**

**Texas A&M University**, College Station, TX, USA Sep 2019 – Dec 2023 (Expected)

Ph.D. students, Department of Computer Science & Engineering

Advisor: Prof. Xia (Ben) Hu

**Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications**, Beijing, CHINA Sep 2015 – June 2019

M.S. in Computer Science Advisor: Prof. Chuan Shi

Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, CHINA Sep 2011 – June 2015

B.S. in Information and Communication Engineering

# **Professional Experiences**

Meta, Menlo Park, CA Sept 2022 – present

Research Intern

Understanding graph neural networks

Mentor: Qifan Wang

Snap Research, Seattle, WA May 2022 - Aug 2022

Research Intern

Efficient large-scale graph neural networks

Mentor: Neil Shah

Microsoft Research Asian (MSRA), Beijing, China

March 2019 - Jun 2019

Research Intern

Hyperparameter search with Bayesian optimization

Alibaba Group, Hangzhou, China

June 2018 - Sep 2018

Research Intern, Search Business Department

Query recommendation

# **Publications** [Google Scholar]

[Under review] MLPInit: Embarrassingly Simple GNN Training Acceleration with MLP Initialization

Xiaotian Han, Tong Zhao, Yozen Liu, Xia Hu, Neil Shah

2022

[Under review] Do We Really Achieve Fairness with Explicit Sensitive Attributes?

Xiaotian Han, Zhimeng Jiang, Ninghao Liu, Na Zou, Qifan Wang, Xia Hu

2022

[Under review] Marginal Nodes Matter: Towards Structure Fairness in Graphs

Xiaotian Han, Kaixiong Zhou, Ting-Hsiang Wang, Xiao Huang, Jundong Li, Na Zou, Xia Hu

<sup>\*</sup> indicates equal contribution.

2022 [Under review] Retiring  $\Delta DP$ : New Distribution-Level Metrics for Demographic Parity Xiaotian Han, Zhimeng Jiang, Hongye Jin, Zirui Liu, Na Zou, Qifan Wang, Xia Hu [Under review] Fair Graph Message Passing with Transparency Zhimeng Jiang, **Xiaotian Han**, Chao Fan, Zirui Liu, Na Zou, Ali Mostafavi, Xia Hu Topology Matters in Fair Graph Learning: a Theoretical Pilot Study [Under review] Zhimeng Jiang, Xiaotian Han, Chao Fan, Zirui Liu, Xiao Huang, Na Zou, Ali Mostafavi, Xia Hu [ICML 2022] G-Mixup: Graph Augmentation for Graph Classification Xiaotian Han, Zhimeng Jiang, Ninghao Liu, Xia Hu International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2022 Outstanding Paper Award [ICLR 2022] **Generalized Demographic Parity for Group Fairness** Zhimeng Jiang, **Xiaotian Han**, Chao Fan, Fan Yang, Xia Hu, International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022 Graph Representation Learning via Unsupervised Rate Reduction Maximization [WWW 2022] Xiaotian Han, Zhimeng Jiang, Ninghao Liu, Xia Hu The Web Conference (WWW), 2022 [Recsys 2020] **AutoRec: An Automated Recommender System** Ting-Hsiang Wang, Qingquan Song, Xiaotian Han, Zirui Liu, Jin Haifeng, Xia Hu ACM Conference on Recommender Systems (Recsys), 2020 FlowScope: Spotting Money Laundering Based on Graphs, [AAAI 2020] Xiangfeng Li, Shenghua Liu, Zifeng Li, Xiaotian Han, Chuan Shi, Bryan Hooi, He Huang, Xueqi Cheng AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020 [WWWJ 2020] **Embedding Geographic Information for Anomalous Trajectory Detection** Ding Xiao, Li Song, Ruijia Wang, Xiaotian Han, Yanan Cai, Chuan Shi World Wide Web. 2020 [KDD 2020] Metapath-guided Heterogeneous Graph Neural Network for Intent Recommendation Shaohua Fan, Junxiong Zhu, **Xiaotian Han**, Chuan Shi, Linmei Hu, Biyu Ma, Yongliang Li SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (**KDD**), 2019 [TKDE 2019] Deep Collaborative Filtering with Multi-aspect Information in Heterogeneous Networks Chuan Shi, Xiaotian Han, Li Song, Xiao Wang, Senzhang Wang, Junping Du, Philip, S Yu IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering (**TKDE**), 2019 Representation Learning with Depth and Breadth for Recommendation using Multi-view Data [APWeb 2018] Xiaotian Han, Chuan Shi, Lei Zheng, Philip, S Yu, Jianxin Li, Yuanfu Lu APWeb-WAIM International Joint Conference on Web and Big Data (APWeb-WAIM), 2018 [IJCAI 2018] Aspect-Level Deep Collaborative Filtering via Heterogeneous Information Networks

Xiaotian Han, Chuan Shi, Senzhang Wang, Philip, S Yu, Li Song International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2018

[ADMA 2018] **Anomalous Trajectory Detection Using Recurrent Neural Network** 

Li Song, Ruijia Wang, Ding Xiao, **Xiaotian Han**, Yanan Cai, Chuan Shi

International Conference on Advanced Data Mining and Applications (ADMA), 2018

Best Paper Awards

### **Professional Services**

### Program Committee Member/Reviewer

International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM) 2022 The ACM Web Conference (**WWW**) 2023 Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2022 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2022 AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2021, 2022, 2023 International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) 2021

### Volunteer International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2022 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL) 2022 **Session Chair** International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2022 Scholarships, Awards, & Honors Travel Grant, Texas A&M University, Department of CSE 2022 Travel Award, ICML2022 2022 Outstanding Reviewer Award, ICML2022 2022 Best Reviewer Award, CCF Transactions on Pervasive Computing and Interaction 2019

2018

National Graduate Scholarship, Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications